

CONTACT ME AT

Quito, Ecuador

info@francoacg.com

www.francoacg.com

in @francoacg

SKILLS SUMMARY

- PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Flutter
- Highcharts
- React.js, React Native, Vue.js, Redux
- MaterializeCSS, TailwindCSS
- Git Github Gitlab Gitea Bitbucket
- Linux commands Docker
- Test Driven Development
- RESTful, Node.js, Express.js
- Python
- Rust
- Object Oriented Programming
- Regular Expressions
- Native Spanish, English C1

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2016 ACM-ICPC Coding Marathon
- Improved the workflow on the companies I've worked on
- Gameboy emulator written in Rust
- My website where you can find more personal highlights!

HOBBIES

- Develop videogames or emulators in my spare times
- Learn new technologies and languages
- Experiment with hardware

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

FRANCO COLMENAREZ

ABOUT ME

I'm a Software Developer with 4+ years of experience working onsite and remotely as a Backend and Frontent developer, creating software solutions for many clients. Learning something new every single day, and helping other developers to keep growing!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Contractor

Amaya Editing (Canada, remotely) | Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

- Backend (PHP, Laravel) and Frontend (Javascript, Vue.js) development
- Unit Testing with Laravel
- Creation of Laravel Artisan commands
- API integrations with Shopify and Astro Loyalty

Software Developer

Aleli (Paraguay, remotely) | Jul 2018 - Jan 2022

- Backend (PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter) and Frontend (Javascript, Vue.js, Svelte, jQuery) development
- Created a **Docker container** for the project
- Created an Android app for a restaurant in React Native
- Re-created the app with Flutter with better performance and more features
- Created a project template in Laravel and Vue.js with backend testing
- Deployed systems for multiple clients
- Complex SQL queries and database migrations
- Improved the performance of multiple modules
- Git and Bitbucket with Git-flow

Software Developer

Dago C.A. (Venezuela, on-site) | Oct 2017 - Mar 2018

- Weight control systems
- Backend (Company's own PHP framework, Express.js) and Frontend (HTML/CSS/Javascript, ¡Query)
- Team work with Git-flow and Gitlab

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

College IUT-FRP | Venezuela

Software Engineering | 2018

- Programming fundamentals: Pointers, Recursion, Binary trees, Object Oriented Programming
- Web development: HTML/CSS, PHP, SQL Databases

Self-taught education

Programming | 2012 - Infinite

- Online education platforms such as Platzi
- Online resources, books and tutorials
- Personal Projects
- Coding challenges